Alisson Ricardo

Las Vegas, NV 89103 | 702-635-2812 | alissonricardo68@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Passionate about front-end designing, testing, and back-end development – especially with Javascript. Built out 4 projects from scratch – 2 full stack and 2 front end – while continuing to build in and learn React Native & C++ independently. Previous professional experience in customer service has brought on versatile collaborative and organizational skills with peers of all backgrounds, in all situations.

SKILLS

Languages: Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Libraries and Frameworks: React, Express.js, Jquery, Bootstrap, Material UI, Bulma, Materialize, Flask

Databases and other: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RESTful Routing, JSON API

Interpersonal skills: Communication, Decision-Making, Active Listening, Teamwork, Positive Attitude,

Self-Learning, Time Management, Customer/Client Empathy

PROJECTS

Gamers, On Record - GitHub - Python | React | Material UI | Flask | Node.js

Full CRUD app with a gaming API where users can log in to share posts about games or browse through them.

- Implemented back-end services with CRUD capabilities, user authentication, and API endpoint requests.
- Used new skills doing this second project with React, like Context Providers and Hooks, that made the passing of properties throughout components more efficient.
- Taught myself to use Material UI with React, making styling a lot of the components simpler and neater.

The Music Box - GitHub - Node.js | Mongoose | EJS | Express | Bulma

Full CRUD app where people can share music and add to the collection page to browse through.

- Built back-end services to allow for users to post, delete, or update data into the app.
- Wrote code that could handle processing real time data entered by a user about their song/album.
- Styled a clean UI and interface for users to browse and submit/update any of the data in the app.

Pot Smash Simulator '97 - GitHub - CSS | JavaScript | Canvas

HTML5 Canvas game where you play as a character that tries destroying as many pots in a certain timeframe.

- Learned a new API (Canvas) independently to create the displayed area and logic for the game.
- Designed a simple but efficient UI for the player to see the stats, time left, and gameplay.
- Animated movement for the player using key presses and waves of enemies coming down!

EXPERIENCE

CCSD - Computer Technician

Curren

> Supporting over 1200 students and staff with printers, computers, interactive flat panels, tablets, and more, as well as year-round inventory tracking & maintenance. IT Ticket requests average at about 30 per week.

Orleans - Dispatcher 04/2023 - 02/2024

This role is vital to housekeeping productivity and includes answering calls, logging exact details, and managing requests for 100's of guests, as well as all staff, and communicating effectively while being able to multitask and keep track of records or other reports that are requested daily.

Asurion - Tech Support Rep

05/2020 - 05/2022

Managed 60 - 80 customer chats daily and increased monthly home insurance sales by 10% with the team. Additionally, raised bug concerns and feature requests to the development team as needed.

Sykes - Tech Support Rep

10/2018 - 05/2020

➤ Delivered premier customer experience to 40 - 50 PlayStation players via chat/phone per day, significant involvement in maintaining services and relaying info on products, services, billing, and more.

EDUCATION